<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Bicycling | Christian Oestreich]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.christianoestreich.com/blog/categories/bicycling/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.christianoestreich.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-13T20:45:33+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.christianoestreich.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Christian Oestreich]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tuesday Night Worlds - 4/19/2011]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.christianoestreich.com/2011/05/tuesday-night-worlds-4192011/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-02T13:58:43+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.christianoestreich.com/2011/05/tuesday-night-worlds-4192011</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another week&hellip; another race.  The crowd was a little bit thinner for this
race as the weather was a warm 36F.  With the absence of Patrick and his
rockets, the group stayed a little more tightly coupled.  Colin was also
absent leaving just Mitch, Chris and myself to represent team OptumHealth
Performance.</p>

<p>On the first sprint lap I decided to take the outside line and Chris grabbed
onto my rear wheel.  I death pulled him for a half lap.  I quickly petered out
up the hill but Chris had enough gas to go hard to the finish line and earn
the teams first 5 points with a first place sprint lap victory.  After the
pull I was struggling to regain the group and didn&rsquo;t reconnect for two laps.
I really tried to use the downhills to my advantage to cover distance.</p>

<p>None of us really had any juice to go for the second sprint lap.  It was just
enough to hang onto the group until the last lap.  We tried the best we could
to get into position for the last lap.</p>

<p>At the bell Chris and I were somewhere in the 6-9 range.  The group quickly
became a single file pace line and we just grabbed a wheel and rode the line
until the uphill portion.  Everyone got up and started sprinting.  I couldn&rsquo;t
make up any ground, but I didn&rsquo;t lose any either.  Chris managed a 3rd place
finish and earned another 2 points.  Overall it was definitely a good night
for the team and especially Chris.</p>

<p>I finished 7th overall and that felt pretty good for the 2nd criterium of my
racing career.  I will respect Mitch&rsquo;s feelings and not talk about where he
finished the event.  I think his wheel fell off this time or something?!</p>

<p>[caption id=&ldquo;attachment_99&rdquo; align=&ldquo;aligncenter&rdquo; width=&ldquo;702&rdquo;
caption=&ldquo;OptumHealth Performance Team (Mitch Talbot, Chris Frykman, Patrick
Parish, Colin Jaworski, Christian Oestreich) &rdquo;]<a href="http://www.christianoestreich.com/wp-"><img src="http://www.christianoestreich.com/wp-" alt="" /></a>[/caption]</p>

<p>content/uploads/2011/05/optumhealth_performance_team.jpg (OptumHealth
Performance Team)</p>

<p>content/uploads/2011/05/optumhealth_performance_team.jpg</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tuesday Night Worlds - 4/12/2010]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.christianoestreich.com/2011/04/tuesday-night-worlds-4122010/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-13T23:34:16+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.christianoestreich.com/2011/04/tuesday-night-worlds-4122010</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a member of the <a href="http://www.optumhealthperformance.com/" title="OptumHealth Performance">OptumHealth Performance</a> road racing team, we did our
first criterium Tuesday night.  It was the <a href="http://www.loonstate.org/" title="Tuesday Night Worlds">Tuesday Night Worlds</a> in the
Opus complex.  You can view the course at Map My Ride <a href="http://www.mapmyride.com/routes/view/406363" title="Map My Ride">course map</a>.</p>

<p>Our strategy was to stay in the top 25% of the group and ride strong.  Things
went as planned for the first two laps.  After that, Patrick was on his own
and rode the remainder of the race out in the front group.  It was an amazing
effort by the whole team for our first criterium showing.</p>

<p>Mitch dropped a chain on the first lap and was left on his own in no-mans-land
for 5 or so laps until the group caught him again.  He grabbed back onto the
group and hung strong through the rest of the race.</p>

<p>After the race we thought Colin and Patrick both both received points for
sprints, but it turns out that all their efforts will in vein as they sprinted
a lap early every time.  Now that we understand WHEN the sprints are we hope
to get points for some of the riders next race.</p>

<p>The biggest surprise was Chris Frykman who, before Tuesday, I had only met on
Facebook and heard about through the teammates.  He pulled like a locomotive
up the hills in what I think was his 53x12 gear.  He was a power climbing
machine.</p>

<p>My race went off without a hitch.  I led out the first lap and dropped back
after the second and faded off the lead group into the second group.  I think
I spent too much too early and eventually was playing yo-yo off the back of
that group.  I finished just off the second group.  I sat up more than I
should have, but after Patrick and the lead group were out of sight I was just
trying to find some relief from the pain in my legs and lungs.  I am still
dislodging phlegm from my lungs that apparently accumulated over the winter.
I haven&rsquo;t ever wheezed like this for so long after a race.  I think that is a
testament on how hard we were riding.</p>

<p>I did a quick graph for the speed of the riders per lap. <em>Mitch&rsquo;s data for lap
5 is missing due to being caught by the group on that lap so I skipped him
even with the group.</em></p>

<p><img src="http://chart.apis.google.com/chart?chxr=0,1,9|1,15,25&amp;chxt=x,y&amp;chs=500" alt="Speed By Lap" /></p>

<p>x400&amp;cht=lxy&amp;chco=3072F3,FF0000,FF9900,66AA00,FF9999&amp;chds=1,9,15,25,1,9,15,25,
1,9,15,25,1,9,15,25,1,9,15,25&amp;chd=t:1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9|21.9,22.9,21.9,20.4,20.6
,20,19.8,19.1,19.2|1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9|22,23.5,21.9,21,21.8,20.8,20.4,21.8,20.5|
1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9|20.7,18.1,17.2,17.2,0,17.1,19,19.5,20.4|1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9|22
,23.1,22,20.4,20.3,20.6,19.7,19.4,20.8|1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9|22,24,20.9,20.6,20.7,
19.9,19.7,20,20.7&amp;chdl=Christian|Patrick|Mitch|Chris|Colin&amp;chdlp=b&amp;chg=0,0,0,0
&amp;chls=1|1|1|1|1&amp;chma=5,5,5,25&amp;chtt=Speed+By+Lap</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
